https://www.raymondcorp.com/privacy-policy

SHOP
Find Your Service Center:
Raymond
Zip or Postal Code:
Automated Guided Vehicles
Raymond Basics - Buy Online!
Automated Guided Vehicles
Raymond Basics - Buy Online!
Last Updated: December 5, 2019
This Privacy Policy (“Policy”) describes the data collected (“Collected Data”) by or on behalf of The Raymond Corporation (“Raymond,” “we,” “us,” or “our”) or its suppliers through this website (“Site”), and how Collected Data is used and shared. If you have questions or concerns about this Policy, please contact us using the information provided below.
By using the Site, you agree on behalf of yourself and any organization that you represent (together, “you”) that you have read and understand this Policy. We may modify this Policy at any time. All changes will be effective immediately upon posting to the Site. Material changes will be conspicuously posted on the Site or otherwise communicated to you. By using the Site after changes are posted, you agree to those changes.
We Collect Data You Voluntarily Provide
Personal Data. You can visit and use the Site without providing any data that personally identifies you.  If you elect to provide to us any data that personally identifies you, such as your name, email and mailing address, phone number, or payment data (“Personal Data”), we will collect it and use it pursuant to this Privacy Policy and applicable law.
Although you do not have to disclose Personal Data to visit our Site, you must provide certain Personal Data to use certain Site features. For example, you must provide your contact data to: place an order, contact us via email, phone, or various Contact forms (where we will retain the content of your form submission); receive or request data from us; and respond to communications from us (e.g., surveys and promotional offers).We use Personal Data as described below.
Raymond Accounts. To create an online Raymond account, you must provide certain Personal Data, and create a password. This data is used to populate a profile within your account.
Order & Payment Data. To make purchases through the Site, you will need to submit your name, credit or debit card type, number, expiration date, security code, and billing address. You may also need to submit purchase order data, if applicable. Payment by credit or debit card is subject to the card issuer’s approval. We will not be liable in any way if a card issuer refuses to accept a transaction for any reason. All credit and debit card data is provided directly to our PCI-compliant third-party payment processor. We do not directly access, handle, or store your credit or debit card data. We may maintain a record of your purchases through the Site. We will store the last four digits of your payment card to facilitate future orders via the Site.
Marketing Communications. If you opt-in to receive marketing communications from us, you will need to submit your Personal Data. We use this data to provide you with promotional and other electronic and hard copy communications. We may use third-party providers to deliver communications to you, which may include research surveys.  You may opt out of receiving such communications by using the unsubscribe link in the applicable email or contacting us at replies@raymondcorp.com with “Unsubscribe” in the subject line. To opt out of other forms of marketing, such as postal marketing or telemarketing, if applicable, then please contact us at 1-800-235-7200.
Job Application Materials. To submit job application materials, you will be redirected to our online job applications portal, which is hosted by ADP. You may be prompted to create an ADP account. All data related to job applications is submitted directly through the ADP site and will then be shared with us. We encourage you to review ADP’s terms and privacy policy. If you submit job application materials, we may use the contents to evaluate your qualifications and to respond to you. Submission of such materials does not guarantee review or consideration for employment.
Legal Basis for Processing Your Personal Data (EEA Only)
If you are an individual from the European Economic Area (“EEA”), our legal basis for collecting and using Personal Data will depend on the Personal Data concerned and the specific context in which we collect it. However, we will normally collect Personal Data from you only where: (a) we have your consent to do so; (b) where we need the Personal Data to perform a contract with you (e.g., to deliver goods or services you have purchased requested); or (c) where the processing is in our or a third party’s legitimate interests and not overridden by your data protection interests or fundamental rights and freedoms. In some cases, we may also have a legal obligation to collect Personal Data from you or may otherwise need the Personal Data to protect your vital interests or those of another person.
If we ask you to provide Personal Data to comply with a legal requirement or to perform a contract with you, we will make this clear at the relevant time and will advise you 1) if the provision of your Personal Data is mandatory, and 2) the possible consequences if you do not provide your Personal Data. Similarly, if we collect and use your Personal Data in reliance on our or a third party’s legitimate interests that are not already described in this Privacy Policy, we will make clear to you at the relevant time what those legitimate interests are.
If you have any questions about or need further data concerning the legal basis on which we collect and use your Personal Data, please contact us.
Data Automatically Collected During Site Use
Account Activity. We may collect data about how you use (i) your online account, and (ii) the Site when you are logged into your account.
IP Addresses; Cookies & Similar Tracking Technologies. When you use the Site, we and our Site providers use various technologies such as cookies (i.e., small pieces of data stored on your device’s hard drive by your browser), tokens, web beacons, pixel tags, and other similar technologies to automatically collect internet protocol addresses assigned to the computers and other devices you use, your internet service provider, device ID number, approximate geographic location , and browser type, Site pages and websites you access before and after visiting the Site, data related to how and when you use the Site (e.g., date and time stamps, clickstream data, and data about search terms and websites that direct you to the Site).  In some countries, including countries in the EEA this data may be considered personal data under applicable data protection laws. We may combine this Collected Data with other Collected Data (including Personal Data) and data obtained from third parties.
Most browsers automatically accept cookies. You can disable this function in your browser settings, but disabling cookies may impact your use and enjoyment of the Site.
Due to the automatic collection of data using cookies, we currently do not honor “do not track” requests.
Analytics. From time to time, we may enable and implement various analytics tools, such as Google Analytics.  Google Analytics is an analytics tool provided by Google Inc. to collect and process Collected Data consisting of certain data about your use of the Site. Google sets and reads cookies to collect such Collected Data and your web browser will automatically send such Collected Data to Google. Google uses this data to provide us with reports that we use to improve the Site’s structure, content, and overall user experience, including content personalization and marketing automation.
From time to time, we may enable and implement additional add-on services to Google Analytics solutions, such as Demographics and Interest Reporting. Demographics and Interest Reporting uses a third-party cookie to collect information about our Site traffic by tracking users across websites and across time.
For more information on how Google uses Collected Data, visit Google’s Policy and Google’s page on How Google uses data when you use our partners’ sites or apps. You may download and install the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on for each web browser you use. Using the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on does not prevent (i) the use of other analytics tools, or (ii) sending data to the Site or to Google. For more data about Google Analytics cookies, visit Google Analytics Cookie Usage on Websites.
Online Behavioral Advertising. From time to time we may use advertising networks and services provided by third-party technology vendors and research firms. These services collect certain data related to your interactions with the Site and other websites and use such data to target personal content and advertisements for goods and services. The data collected may be associated with your Personal Data. These targeted communications and advertisements may appear on the Site and on other websites and may be sent to you via email. Advertising networks often gather data about consumers who view advertisements to make inferences about a consumer’s interests and preferences, which enables their computers to deliver advertisements directly targeted to the consumer’s specific interests. This practice is often referred to as “online behavioral advertising.”
For example, we may use Google Ads to serve ads on our behalf across the internet. Google uses cookies and other similar tracking technologies to collect information about your visits to the Site and your interaction with our products and services to generate targeted advertisements to you on other websites that you visit across the internet. To opt out of remarketing advertising provided through Google, to customize your ad preferences, or to limit Google’s collection or use of such data, visit Google’s Safety Center and Google’s Ad Settings and follow Google’s personalized ad opt-out instructions. Opting out will not affect your use of the Site.
To change your preferences with respect to certain online ads and to obtain more data about third-party ad networks and online behavioral advertising, please visit the National Advertising Initiative Consumer opt-out page or the Digital Advertising Alliance Self-Regulatory Program. Please remember that changing your settings with individual browsers or ad networks will not necessarily carry over to other devices, browsers or ad networks. As a result, depending on the opt-outs you request, you may still see our ads from time to time.
Social Media. The Site may allow you to connect to and share content with various social media platforms (“platforms”), for example, Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, YouTube, and Google+. These features may require us to implement cookies, plug-ins, and application protocol interfaces (APIs) provided by those platforms to facilitate those communications and features. We may share Collected Data with those platforms and that data will be subject to their privacy policies. We encourage you to review their privacy policies: Facebook’s Data Policy; Twitter’s Policy; LinkedIn’s Policy; and Google’s Policy. We cannot control such platforms’ polices or terms, so we are not responsible for any platforms’ use of your data or content. Use these platforms at your own risk.
The Site may use those platforms’ advertising services to deliver advertising content. These services require platforms to implement cookies or pixel tags to deliver ads to you while you are logged into the platform. To prevent platforms from collecting your data via the Site, we suggest that you: (a) do not connect to or share data with that platform using the Site; (b) hide social media platform plug-ins using an ad blocker (disable in your browser settings); (c) always log off completely from the platform before visiting other websites and delete all related cookies; and, (d) where the option is available, disable the advertising services and networks operated by that platform (e.g., you may opt out of Twitter’s interest-based advertising by notifying Twitter here).
We are active on social media, including Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, YouTube, and Google+. We may post on our Site and platform pages and otherwise respond to any content that you post on our platform pages. We will be held harmless and without liability for third-party reposts to other locations, including the direct or assumed meaning regarding content from all our platform pages.
Embedded Content. The Site may incorporate content, including feeds scripts embedded in the Site’s code and visible content, provided by third parties. Those third parties may collect data about how you interact with their content (e.g., YouTube may collect usage data on videos embedded on the Site as described in YouTube’s Policy).
Data from Other Sources. We obtain data about individuals from various third-party companies and public sources and we may combine this data with Personal Data or other Collected Data that we may have about you. This enhances our existing data about our users and customers (e.g., adding address data) and improves our ability to contact you and our marketing’s relevancy.
How We Use and Share Collected Data
Beyond the uses and sharing described above, Raymond and its suppliers may use and disclose Collected Data as described below. We do not sell or rent Collected Data except as stated in this Policy and as permitted by applicable law.
Purpose Collected & Communication with You. We use and share Collected Data for the purpose for which it was collected. For example, if you contact us for support or assistance, we may use Collected Data to contact you and assist you with your request. We may use Collected Data to notify you of Site changes (e.g., changes to our Terms of Use or this Policy), and if you opt in to receive marketing communications from us, to send you those communications.
Sharing Collected Data with Our Sales and Service Centers. We may share Collected Data with our Sales and Service Centers. For example, if you purchase a product online, we will need to share your order information, including your contact and payment data with our local Sales and Service Center so they may fulfill your order and otherwise communicate with you.
Third-Party Suppliers and Consultants. We may share your Personal Data and other Collected Data with our affiliates, third-party service providers, suppliers, consultants, agents, distributors, sales representatives, resellers, and other partners (including Site management and hosting suppliers, payment processors, marketing and public relations service providers, and email service suppliers) that provide data processing services to us (e.g., to support the delivery of, provide functionality on, or help to enhance the security of the Site or our websites, services, or products) or who otherwise process Personal Data for purposes that are described in this Privacy Policy or communicated to you when we collect your Personal Data. Our suppliers are authorized to and may use and disclose Collected Data as necessary for them to provide the applicable services to us and as provided by their own privacy policies.
Aggregated Data. We may use Collected Data to create aggregate data that is anonymized. We may use and share such aggregate data with our affiliates, Sales and Service Centers, suppliers, and other third parties to: analyze, develop, and improve the content, materials, products, and services that we make available, inform business strategies, understand the Site’s demographics and user preferences, customize promotional emails and users’ Site experience, including personalization and automation of content, and for other lawful purposes.
Security & Protection of Rights. We may use Collected Data and share it with third parties if we believe it is necessary to operate the Site or to protect our rights or the rights of others, including disclosing data necessary to identify, contact, or bring legal action if our contracts, terms, or policies are violated, or if required pursuant to a law enforcement or legal requirement.
Business Transactions.  All Collected Data is exclusively our property.  However, we undergo corporate transactions from time to time, such as changes in control, acquisitions, mergers, reorganizations, or asset sales. We may share Collected Data with third parties in connection with the evaluation of those transactions.   In addition, we may transfer Collected Data if we enter into those transactions. In addition, if we (or our assets) are acquired or if we go out of business, enter bankruptcy, or go through some other change of control or reorganization, Personal Data and other Collected Data could be one of the assets transferred to or acquired by a third party  .
With Your Consent. With your consent, we may use or share Collected Data in ways not specifically described in this Policy.
International Transfers of Your Personal Data
In operating the Site, your Personal Data may be transferred to, stored in, and processed in countries other than the country in which you are resident. Those countries may have data protection laws that are different from those of your country and, in some cases, may not be as protective. Specifically, our website servers and some of our service providers are located in the United States and our affiliated companies and third-party service providers and partners operate around the world. This means that when we collect your Personal Data we may process it in other countries.
We have, however, taken appropriate safeguards to require that your Personal Data will remain protected in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
How Long We Retain Your Personal Data
We will retain your Personal Data for as long as is needed to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law (e.g., tax, accounting, or other legal requirements ). We will securely store your Personal Data until deletion is possible.
With regard to Personal Data collected using Google Analytics as discussed above, that data will be retained for 26 months after your last activity on the Site.
If you are a customer, we will retain that Personal Data in accordance with the terms of our customer or other agreement with you, subject to applicable law.
Your Rights and Choices Regarding Your Personal Data
You have the following data protection rights:
If you wish to access, correct, update, or request deletion of your Personal Data, you can do so at any time by visiting your account or contacting us at replies@raymondcorp.com.
In addition, if you are a resident of the European Economic Area, you can object to the processing of your Personal Data, you can ask us to restrict processing of your Personal Data, and you can request portability of your Personal Data. You can exercise these rights by contacting us at replies@raymondcorp.com.
Similarly, if we have collected and process your Personal Data with your consent, then you can withdraw your consent at any time. Withdrawing your consent will not affect the lawfulness of any processing we conducted prior to your withdrawal, nor will it affect processing of your Personal Data conducted in reliance on lawful processing grounds other than consent. This does not necessarily require us to delete your Personal Data with respect to transactions we have previously entered into.
You have the right to complain to the United States Federal Trade Commission or other data protection authority about our collection and use of your Personal Data. For more data please contact your local data protection authority. Contact data for data protection authorities in the EEA, Switzerland, and certain non-European countries (including the United States and Canada) are available here.
We respond to all requests we receive from individuals wishing to exercise their data protection rights in accordance with applicable data protection laws.
Third-Party Websites
The Site may link to, or be linked to, websites not controlled by us. We are not responsible for third-parties’ privacy policies or practices. This Policy does not apply to any third-party websites or to any data that you provide to third parties. You should read the privacy policy for each website that you visit.
Data Security
Data storage and transmission can never be completely secure. We do not guarantee that loss, misuse, or alteration of Collected Data will not occur. We use appropriate technical and organizational measures to ensure a level of security appropriate to the risk for all Personal Data processed.  This Site has commercially reasonable security measures in place to help protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control.  In the event that a breach into our security systems occurs and there is a possibility that an unauthorized person acquires your Personal Information, we will notify you of the breach if and as required under applicable law.
Children
We are committed to protecting children’s privacy. The Site is not directed at children under 18 years of age. We do not knowingly collect, use, or share data from children under 18. If a parent or legal guardian learns their child provided us with Personal Data without his or her consent, please contact us.
California Residents
Click here to view the Privacy Policy for California Residents.
Nevada Consumers
Although we do not currently sell your Personal Data, Nevada law gives Nevada consumers the right to opt-out of any future sale of your Personal Data in the unlikely event we change our practices. To exercise this right please contact us at replies@raymondcorp.com.
Contact Us
If you have any questions or concerns regarding this Policy, contact us at:
The Raymond Corporation
Attn. Marketing Communications
22 South Canal Street,
Greene, NY 13778
Phone: 800-235-7200
Email: replies@raymondcorp.com
We use cookies on this website to deliver the best possible experience. For more on how we use cookies and how to change them, go here.
By continuing to use our site, you are giving us your consent to use cookies.
